Kevin Phelps

309 Hillcrest Dr Saline, MI 48176 (734) 972-0619 KJPhelps90@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

Reliable, hard-working project manager and data analyst with 6 years of experience in data analysis. I've had great success creating and maintaining positive client relationships over the past several years leading me to my current role. I have experience cleaning data along with writing syntax in several different coding languages including C++, SQL, Java, and SPSS.

EXPERIENCE

Customer Insights Consultant – CFI Group – Ann Arbor, MI

JULY 2019 - July 2021

- Sole project manager and data resource for a mortgage satisfaction and benchmarking project. The project includes 40 clients and four surveys, with an annual revenue of nearly \$1,000,000.
- Responsible for new customer onboarding, working with client contacts to create several automated processes to receive and send out surveys.
- Quickly diagnosing and solving problems in all areas of the survey process.
- Designing quarterly presentations where I provide personalized in-depth analysis.

Senior Data Operations Specialist – CFI Group – Ann Arbor, MI

JULY 2017 – JUNE 2019

- Creating, updating, and maintaining dozens of customer satisfaction surveys.
- Cleaned and formatted received data to create data cubes used in reporting.
- Transformed data to create new variables in C++, SQL, and SPSS.
- Implemented and maintained reporting UI's for over 50 clients.
- Monitored various ETL's, FTP sites, and API calls to ensure all processes are working as expected.
- Responsible for creating and updating over 100 reporting hierarchies and managing data access to thousands of users.

Business Research Developer – CFI Group – Ann Arbor, MI

MARCH 2014 - JUNE 2016

- Worked with project managers and clients to determine data reporting needs
- Produced reports using multiple formats and tools including PowerPoint, Excel, and SPSS.
- Created quality control checklists to ensure data integrity.

EDUCATION

Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, MI – Bachelor's in Finance